The news is over. This
is Kang Ji-young from New Seol, a new story different
from the news. We
wanted to have some time to laugh in the news. The other
news today was a bit heavy, but I
hope you have a fun time watching the news. Well, no other explanation is needed.
Everything is explained with science. We've brought you this possible
science communicator,
Orbiter.
Hello.
Actually, it's a little embarrassing to say that we're not called,
but the
episode that came out for the first time really
became a hot topic. It
became a hot topic in the market. Rather
than saying that I did a good job, he smiled a little too
brightly, and other people liked that smile. I'm starting to
wonder if he's really affected me. He's smiling like that, but he's
not cool at all, and he's talking about himself like a maniac. I guess he
didn't have time. It lasted 30 minutes, but
if I had time, I'd laugh a little too, but
I don't have time.
I will be here in about 2 hours, but I have
a lot to do today, so I will have a lot of time. Okay,
now that the fall season has passed, the wind blowing in the evening has
definitely changed a bit compared to midsummer.
Autumn is getting closer and closer,
so today is the day to welcome fall. Let's
start with a composed New Year's poem.
I'll read it to you.
One jujube. Jang Seok-ju. That thing ca
n't
turn red on its own. A few typhoons in there, a few thunderstorms. Before a few cliffs, a few lightning bolts come in and turn red. I wake up. There's no way that thing can turn round on its own. It's
scary inside there. A
few nights ago, the scorching sun, a couple of months ago, a
few months before the new moon, the
thing that makes it round is waking up.
Jujube, you have communicated with the world.
How do you guys feel? I started with a single jujube, and
while it felt good, now it
is shining in the eyes of the phantom thief. Is it
possible to explain it with
science? It's almost
textbook-like in science because it can be explained with science. This is a really good
poem. It's a textbook. It's
perfect. Let's take this as an example and
look at the astronomical book.
That can't turn red on its own. This
science is constantly doubting and
verifying. Well, it's already just blowing.
From that point on, the jujube started to turn red on its own. Then, we go in with
suspicion. It's the start of completely scientific thinking.
So, starting from the first line, we are
constantly doubting and not easily convinced. This
part shows completely scientific thinking. The
phenomenon itself of the jujube bulging is
actually true. It's a very simple thing.
Even this is a sentence declaring that we will use scientific thinking to find the cause. It was a declaration.
So, let's
take it step by step.
Next time, there will be a typhoon inside there. Actually, a
typhoon or thunder
cannot go inside there. No, no, there is no such
thing. Let's move on to poetic permission. If
we do this, we
won't be able to get in. The typhoon is
almost as big as a city. Oh, that's right. Okay, okay, let's
skip this. I understand. First of all, I
think of it as an experience that is a little inside. There's a
typhoon inside there. Thunder and lightning are an experience.
But if you look at them, they
say there are several typhoons. Typhoons are usually
counted as one or two. They usually
call them by name,
but they also say one, two, etc. How
many typhoons came this year,
but from then on. Now, it's a bit
difficult. In the
case of thunder, it's an
atmospheric discharge phenomenon that accompanies lightning, but in this
case, it's a
wave that passes through this medium.
So, there are
several at the same time. So, it
may be a little difficult to say just a few thunders. You
can't buy thunder. Because you
can't pinpoint the limit, the fact that
thunder strikes itself means the
existence of a medium that exists in countless directions. So, it
doesn't happen like a single thunderbolt strikes. It
thunders. So, first of all, this is a little
difficult. There was and the important thing is that there is a very
good point here about how
many lightning strikes and how many lightning bolts.
In fact,
regardless of what can be counted, if you look at
whether the two are really different,
lightning itself is first of all a cloud and a space
between clouds and the ground surface.
So, the fact is that the phenomenon of electric discharge in the air
occurs between clouds or between clouds and the ground.
First of all,
lightning encompasses all of these, but lightning only
refers to what occurs between clouds and the ground. Oh, then, this is
lightning. It
encompasses everything that happens like this. And the
point of lightning is that most people would not know the difference between the two. It is
also written as lightning. The
poet
deliberately added the two as a way to explain the difference between the two.
I see, you
wanted me to explain it like this, so you were
explaining it like this.
I guess you didn't wait this long because this is the
same period as physics and earth textbooks.
But what's interesting here is that
there are definitely thunderbolts and lightning. Yes, but
the bigger concept here.
Before that, the smaller concept of
thunderbolt
was used repeatedly to emphasize the thunderbolt and lightning itself. For
example, in the case of a typhoon, a typhoon, a
hurricane, etc.
can be used in many ways, but I
said a typhoon once, and
only once a thunderbolt, but
thunderbolt and lightning. This
is a person who is a bit interested in electromagnetism.
This in itself
is a person who likes thunderbolts and lightning.
This
can be a little disappointing or fun, but
usually it is
expressed as thunder, lightning, and lightning. Since it is
written as thunderbolt and lightning, it is
actually a sign of light. The speed is much faster than sound. That's
why
lightning strikes and then thunder comes. That's right. So, in
fact, the
lightning must enter the loan first, and then the thunder. The
order should also be changed. If the
thunder comes in first, the lightning has
already gone out.
Butnow. If
thunder and lightning come after the thunder,
shouldn't the typhoon be the last to go? It's
different from the typhoon, so
they can be seen independently.
But
thunder and lightning are connected, and the
lightning comes first. It's
true that there was thunder. I
think this was also intentional. I deliberately
reversed the order of time.
The sound came first, and then the light came.
This is common knowledge that everyone knows,
but I reversed it. In other words, I wanted to write a work that transcends time and space.
I'm a bit of an emergency. I'm
going for the second time.
As expected, it
shows the mind of a scientist. Doubting
and not being sure. If you
look next to the circle, the number of
nights is not there because there is
sun. There is no.
Then, there
is the scorching sun, so there is no.
Isn't there a crescent moon because there's a sun?
But isn't it always floating, unlike the original sun? That's when I saw it
floating. It's
really great. I'm thinking critically. There are many
situations where the sun is on the other side,
so there's
no sun right now. There's a sun. There's no sun. There's no sun. It's
repeating presence and absence.
What does this mean? It
expresses the rotation of the Earth. As the Earth rotates, the flow of time
creates the presence and absence of the sun. As it
rotates, why does the Earth suddenly
say that jujubes are round and talk about the Earth's rotation?
Aren't you wondering? That's because,
when expressing roundness, the jujube is
not a perfect sphere. It's
roughly safe. In the
case of a perfect Earth, it rotates, so it's
a bit bulging on the equator side.
It's close to an ellipse.
Likewise, it's not a perfect sphere. You
brought up the story of the Earth's rotation to talk about loans and ellipses.
Doesn't that make sense?
So, the great thing is that it's
all come out now. It's about space and time, just the
speed of light and sound, and now
the Earth's rotation, things like that, the equator is
sticking out. Some of you may not know this, so
physics and the Earth are like textbooks.
Talking to the last world.
Aren't we educated through textbooks anymore? All these
comments. In any case,
when you enter a humanities field, you are
given not just humanities knowledge but also science and technology.
Since it is conveying textbook information,
this itself is connected to the world. It is integrated with the
literary world. Everything is connected to time through the integration of science and science.
That's right. Your threshold for laughter has risen a lot. No no no, I am calm.
My code name is
bursting or not. That's why I think
I
got hurt by allowing that performance today, so you don't allow things like this. I
know I'll never allow it next time. Everyone, this
was just a taste. Let's continue to have a
full-fledged conversation with Gather about the keywords that come to mind when we think of fall.
Please,
fall is the season to read science. I brought autumn shad. There
is a proverb like this.
Even the daughter-in-law who leaves home
comes back when she smells grilling shad.
Now, I can explain this to you. It's such a fun phrase. That's how I know it.
Autumn shad itself is so
delicious that it's a good idea to
cook it.
It means that the scent comes back,
but there are
many things we need to consider right now. For
example, first of all,
isn't the daughter-in-law coming back? Why is it the
daughter-in-law? Why is it the
daughter-in-law? There is a result that women generally have a
better sense of smell.
So, usually. Men are faster at
reacting when we see moving objects. This is
basically why men are good at games.
Men are also better at distinguishing images in detail.
However, in the
case of women, the auditory cells are stronger than
men. It is 20% more developed than that. They
hear sounds very well, and their
sense of smell is also very sensitive, so
women are better than men. So,
especially when it comes to smell,
women are superior at all ages.
So, when grilled gizzard shad. In fact, it is
very appropriate for the daughter-in-law to come here. It
was a reasonable thing to say. For
example, if we change this a little, then the son-in-
law or son who left home will come back.
At this time, you should not grill gizzard shad
because men react much
faster to visuals, so what should we do? The
Pacific giant octopus is about 6 to 10 meters long.
So, it's like this. The
daughter-in-law who ran away is not like this, but the son-in-
law who left home also comes back when he sees the Pacific giant octopus on the terrace. If you
hang it right on the university gate of the terrace,
men will react much faster. Women will react much faster. Since your
sense of smell is more developed, hang a
huge piece of seafood on the terrace to make it visible. If you do this, your son-in-
law or son who left home will
be able to react much faster. Then, if your
daughter-in-law
said that she is coming back because of her sense of smell because she is a woman now, it is
still a good idea for all women. I'm curious. It's a
very good question.
In fact, if you
think about it very simply, the
smell of gizzard shad spreads far away, so
wouldn't your daughter-in-law come back after smelling this? This is a one-dimensional
condition. Just smelling
that
smell and coming back
is just a physical approach to how much it can spread. We must first
think about why the daughter-in-law left the house.
Now the daughter-in-law
has left the house. Your family has left the house and is
now running away. Yes,
then in fact, the possibility of grilling gizzard shad in such a difficult situation is
very low.
How can you make a phone call when your family has left the house? You
are cooking a phone very leisurely right now.
This itself is probably not an emergency situation.
Wasn't there some kind of will? Mother-in-
law's will. That's right, you
can eat it yourself. Anyway, this is
not positive. The current situation
is, but the
daughter-in-law is also not easy. It is very likely that the daughter-in-law
sensed that I might grill the gizzard shad.
In this sentence itself, because in any case, if you
starve, the daughter-in-law will come back. You know, it's
very likely that the writing didn't go far because the returning itself caught the scent. That's why he probably
didn't go far and waited for the smell to come out.
If you interpret it a little more, he
built a contact network with his acquaintances around him. If
the smell from the process of grilling the shad is caught, it is
very likely that he will leave a message in the form of "I will contact you quickly and I will come back quickly."
So, in fact, it is a question of how
far the smell spreads. What is
more important
is that it is
highly likely that this news reached the daughter-in-law's ears without much meaning. So,
in fact, this sentence itself
does not mean that the daughter-in-law returns because the smell of baking is so good. This
situation is in
this
era of baking phones while thoroughly maintaining security. You can see the people and the
daughter-in-law who wants to taste this gizzard shad desperately.
So, I will grill it in secret.
I will somehow
catch this smell and come in. It is a very intense situation right now.
So,
rather than interpreting this as just saying that fall shad is delicious, Wow,
at that time. There
have been such urgent situations.
Life is not easy. It
teaches such a lesson.
So, this sentence is
used when you work a lot of overtime and life is not easy. Hey, they say that if you
grill shad in the fall, your
daughter-in-law will come back.
Ah, I learned a lesson. There
is a quiz that asks about the writer's point of view and intentions,
because it contains a story about the world that is not easy.
The phone is delicious.
Understand the tense situation.
There is no life. You
've talked a lot about fall before and after in the past.
Even now, it's really hot and in fact it's fall. Right
now, it's
from August to October, so a lot of people say it's the season, but at
this time, gizzard shad
consume the most food because it's
very nutritious.
Please leave a comment. What needs to be changed is
because of global warming.
Even in the summer, Cheonho is plump right now.
Between May and July, my phone is also very plump.
How can I change it?
Well, it's actually a good situation.
Because the
sentence itself, about the smell of shad in autumn and the daughter-in-law coming back,
becomes more perfect. Because First of all,
as the temperature rises, the movement of gases becomes
more active. So in fact, odor particles can spread more in the summer than in the fall.
So,
even just looking at the smell,
summer shad is more advantageous than fall, but since
they gain weight even before summer, this sentence is no longer valid.
Wouldn't it be better to change it to pre-summer?
Even my daughter-in-law, who left the house in the summer,
returns desperately when she smells the absence of summer shad. Going further from here, we
could possibly go to winter. If it gets
warmer, no, if we go to winter, it
will be too cold.
In cold conditions, when the temperature drops,
the smell disappears. It doesn't spread very well.
So at this point, it does
n't spread far, it only spreads nearby. So in reality, it doesn't spread this far. And my daughter-in-law
is doing well in delivery classes these days, so she
doesn't leave the house often. Where is this going?
So, I put the sentence like this
next door. I didn't go far. It's all
right anyway. My
daughter-in-law in the next room
comes out to the living room when she smells the summer shad being grilled before and after.
Or, winter shad is also
possible. Because it's possible to go to the next room.
Winter transfer is possible. Oh, I understand. You
can use it in the modern way. Like this, the
proverb is also modernized. I received and watched it and
learned a lot of lessons again.
Please show me the second keyword.
Actually, many people don't know about it, but because it is
so famous, the sky usually gets higher in the fall. It is
called the season of dry fat, but the sky
gets higher. It can be interpreted in a scientific sense.
Is it possible? First of all, what we usually express as the sky
is 100km from the ground.
So if you go beyond this, called the Karman line, it is
space. In other words, the sky
does not get higher. It
changes slightly depending on the height of the ground, but
basically, the sky extends to 100km from the ground.
Because the definition does not change, it is
impossible for the sky to get higher.
So if you want to change this, first of all, the
sky does not get higher. For example, you
can see the distance between the Earth and the Sun.
But
the Sun is floating in space, but we
generally You see it as floating in the sky.
In fact, it is not floating in the sky. The
sun is floating in space. It
is not within 100 km, so I
think they probably did not want to express that the sun is moving away, but this
makes some sense. It is the
distance between the Earth and the Sun. If you look at it, the
closest one is winter. It's a
waste of the sun in winter. So far, it's about
147.5 million km, and the furthest summer is 152.6 million
km.
Why is it the coldest when it's close to winter? It's
close to winter, but our rotation axis It's
tilted, so it's
much colder in the winter and much warmer in the summer. It's
far away, but the
rotation axis is tilted. So don't misunderstand this. It's
not that it gets hot because it's close. The angle of the axis is right.
Ah, now it's
a good common sense
question. Thank you. I give it to you. If you
look at it now, it
is fall. In fall, the sun is quite far away compared to winter. In fall, the sky is
high. How does this part change? In fall, the sun is further
away than in winter. This is an accurate expression. The
sky is the same. Instead, if we
want to express the sun, the sky is higher.
Instead of expressing the trembling sun as the sky,
express it as the real sun of the universe. In autumn, the sun is
further away than in winter, but it is relatively far away, but
closer than summer.
[Music] What makes me
curious is that horses are now
mammals, so does gaining weight apply to all mammals or is
it just horses? First of all, it
makes sense for animals to gain weight, because it
is a season of abundance in preparation for winter. They use this time to
store up as much food as possible. This in
itself has meaning,
but the problem is that
people say things that are completely unrelated to humans, such as paralysis. Let's
put a little bit of weight gain into perspective. The sky is high and the horses
are fat. The
sun is far away and the horses are fat. There is
no one here. But suddenly, he
talks about his paralysis and talks about himself. That's the
problem, but
honestly, this isn't scientific thinking. It's
because the
appetite has increased. There are many reasons, but
this is
not due to the season. Perhaps autumn, which has been still, will be
surprised. If we suddenly talk about edibles, it
will become shorter as we move into fall. When this happens, the
nights become longer and serotonin secretion
decreases.
The nights become longer. Cerato secretion
decreases. This
can cause an increase in appetite. As the
night gets longer and then
the temperature suddenly drops,
more calories are needed to restore body temperature, so
food is needed. That's how
the process goes. Acceptance may increase, but the
important thing is that if you look at it this way, your appetite should increase more in the winter.
However, in the winter, the appetite is delayed, and it
goes back to winter, and in the fall, it
is said that the appetite suddenly increases based on this,
and in the summer, the temperature rises due to air conditioning. It's
low. I'm
still low enough to get an air-conditioning illness. In other words, my
appetite increases in the summer and winter, but it
also comes in the fall.
So what this means is
simply that my appetite is increasing.
I and I are making a
scapegoat for my increased appetite. It's there. Let's see. It's
because of you, Autumn, that you gained weight. No, there's nothing
wrong with Autumn. I'm just jealous.
And to be honest, there
are people who don't have much of an appetite.
That's right, I
don't use the word 'cheongo paralysis' very often. First of all, people who use the word 'cheongo paralysis'
I'm
sure my appetite has increased. I need to self-censor. I'm a
successful business for no reason. It's fall now, and it's the
season for billing laws. When I say that to people like this, I
wonder if I'm falsely accusing fall, who
has nothing to do with it. Please take a look at this. You
provided such an opportunity yourself. I
understand Cheongomabi. Now, show me the next keyword.
Chuseok and science.
Now, when you think of Chuseok,
Chuseok is now next month.
It's at the end of next month.
[Music] I
think what reminds me of fall is Chuseok. When I think of
Chuseok, many people now eat songpyeon.
When making songpyeon, if you make it pretty, you
will get a pretty baby.
Can this be explained scientifically? Have you ever
heard of this story? I am
very grateful to my mother.
This is a very interesting approach, but the fact is that you
really
make the songpyeon very pretty. Myeon-
eun is
saying, Hey, since you make songpyeon so beautifully, you must be really pretty when you have a child,
but in reality, you usually
make songpyeon really well. Then, the
next story is that
you will do well if you open a rice cake shop. Should
you go into business like this? Oh, then we
need to talk about this phenomenon itself. It
is connected to suddenly giving birth to a pretty child.
This itself is probably because people
usually work with pretty people to say that the child is pretty.
Ah, then the latter is the premise first.
Now, that's how it goes. There's a
pretty person who's good at making songpyeon. Come in and say, "I really
believe in songpyeon. You're going to
give birth to a really pretty child. In
some ways, it's a bit of a flirtation.
But for example, my songpyeon
is really a work of art.
But come in and say
songpyeon." He is good at making songpyeon. It could end here.
However, what kind of appearance the child is
born with simply
depends on the combination of genes of the two parents. So, he is
very good at making songpyeon, which he likes very well.
Then, my child will be
very good at making songpyeon. There is a high possibility of being born as a child who makes songpyeon.
That is, I am genetically
good at making songpyeon,
and a person who believes in sexually transmitted diseases is good at making songpyeon. Your child will also be good at making songpyeon in the future,
right? That's right. This is
logical.
But then you
suddenly added the word pretty.
In fact, it seems to be a very difficult approach,
so it is actually difficult to connect the ability to make songpyeon with the
child's appearance. There
is no connection.
People who believe in songpyeon well only give birth to children who believe in songpyeon well.
Because they are good with their hands, and that You will
continue to have children who are good at making songpyeon,
but I've thought about it for a while.
Anyway, the more people move their hands, the
more stimulation they provide to various parts of the brain, so they have
various cognitive abilities or
observational abilities. I think that there will be, and because of that, you
can choose your spouse well. If you
look at it in the long term, if you look at it comprehensively, if you look at it
as a market for scientists, you can
find a good spouse and
have children with just one hand. This is actually the
human relationship. I think we'll almost have to analyze big data. It
might be difficult to just pinpoint it,
but being dexterous is also a
great ability, so
based on that ability, you can meet good people and have good
children. Then, from now
on, when you make songpyeon, someone will do it like this. If you
make it pretty, you'll be a scientist. If you've
planted the mindset of a scientist communicator,
you'll be able to
make songpyeon pretty well, so your
daughter and son will trust songpyeon. This is a
valid comment. That's good, but
I want to tell you this. Actually,
babies are naturally pretty.
So, most babies are pretty.
So, in fact, the statement itself is
not a bad thing. You will give birth to a pretty baby. If
you add a little bit to this, you will now give birth to a pretty baby in your opinion.
Because what we feel is pretty is mainly because it is a
familiar face that is pretty. I feel it.
Usually, all parents say that their baby is
so pretty. Because
what is the appearance that I am most familiar with? When I
look at it through a mirror that I have looked at throughout my life, it
looks prettier because I am so familiar with it.
So, for all parents, their
child is the prettiest and most adorable.
Regardless of whether or not you make songpyeon well,
your baby is pretty. Well, that's a
good thing. So, in fact,
regardless of whether you
made songpyeon beautifully,
rather than saying that your child is pretty, just say that even if you
don't make songpyeon pretty,
your baby will definitely be pretty.
What if you do a lot of
Songpyeon? Regardless of songpyeon,
songpyeon is good at combing.
How can you apply old comments to make them floating
comments? Also, how can you make it
very hot. If
nothing is said, it's a
situation where you don't say anything. Then, why have I been
doing human relationships like this?
It's a time to think about it, and it
's a very symbolic place to look back on human relationships. I can
see that it's a time when we can check a lot of things during Chuseok just by looking at the image of making songpyeon. Ah, I'll give you a quiz at this point,
our orbit.
When you were explaining this, you
said that the sky is defined as the area that is a
few kilometers away from the Earth. If you
leave a few kilometers above the Earth, we will send you a movie ticket.
Ah, I am very good with my hands.
My parents
have very good grandchildren. There is a good chance that
all of our ancestors would have been good with dexterity.
I don't know how the combination did it, but
basically,
within the history close to mine, they must have been quite dexterous.
I believe it
very well. Can you help me? Ah, I'm making other people
like this,
but I Honestly, it's good because it's good to
fix something. I'm
starting like this based on principles and scientific thinking to find out what the cause is. Are there any
big problems? Oh, there are a lot of them. There are so
many. And now,
since I was young, I really like taking things apart, so if something breaks, Let's
fix it first. Let's take it all apart and go back
to the beginning and find out
what the cause is. If we do this, everything
will be solved. In fact, because I suddenly
asked this question, it was a bit different from
usual,
so my attention was very high, and the
whole point of moving my fingers so much was like,
ah, I understand. It was interesting.
Andromeda, the correct answer to the quiz. You
even got the nickname right. It's
good. The correct
answer is 100. The correct answer is 100 km
Andromeda. I'll send you a movie ticket. It's too far, so why don't you
go?
[Laughs]
Oh, if you send it now with humanity's technology,
how much is the closest? The
star is now called Proxima Center Wool, and it
will take more than 80,000 years by spacecraft to get there. If 80,000 is not
reached, it is much further away. It
is 4.2 light years away at the speed of light, and Andro is much
further away, so the movie will already be released. I'll probably
get off. Oh, I'm not carrying it. Please
wait at least 80,000 years. I'll develop it much, much more and send it to you. There's a
faster post
office called Quick Express. I'll
send it to you that way. Okay, I talked
to the phantom thief, a super seller in the ancient world, and
he'll come back next time.
Okay, we'll be
back tomorrow with a new story. Shation,
thank you for watching.
Goodbye,
thank you.
[Music]